[Music]
he
hello good evening good day everybody
and welcome to the latest episode of the
ask show I hope you're all doing great
class is in session let's see who all is
there in attendance tonight today I can
see NES kopal minalin anurag Kap Sumit
Kumar Goos AGA mukad Karan NAD Deli
sidhar sarar Guru Prasad Akil GK pram
Sharma geopolitical Dubay
nikil Nei s bador pritam Sharma Devan
vas EP bio rice absens IPA om vinod
jadav khn siman deep Singh Baga mayure
baby cheeks ABI shorts video rck Raj
adwa Nan Roshan sidhar noan pram SG
rishikes pret if you think you're bad
then I'm your
dad Rishi Patel 3698 user har suan Arjun
Arya Vladimir zaleski Vishnu mahanan
Vishnu Mr Roy abishek T aspirant Neil
Singh Cruz Master Samar Lou Yad toan
Chri me MTI mitul tarun anurag NES
Miguel Diz sag sagaru sagik dat sidat SG
pram and so many other people thank you
so much for being on the live stream and
uh
yeah so as you know dungar Singh Chan vi
vi Kumar Richie and everybody else all
right all right I'm going to stop
greeting you all individually now
because otherwise I'll take all day so
uh let us get going with the questions
today is a live chat live streams I'm
going to take questions only from the
YouTube live chat so go ahead ask me
your questions ask me your best
questions and I will take as many of
these as is possible let's see let us
see let us see what questions do we
have uh okay let us begin with siman
deep Singh bua what are your thoughts on
people having the fear that prime
minister Narendra Modi G is turning into
a
dictator Prime Minister Modi is turning
into a dictator there is fear among the
people which people I wonder okay so
let's take it logically just logically
without any emotions involved in this
okay okay let's consider actual
dictatorships that we are aware of which
dictatorships do we know of we know of
North Korea definitely a dictatorship we
know of China definitely a dictatorship
no no democracy there no such thing okay
so imagine you go to North Korea you go
to pongyang okay and you go to the main
Square in pongyang where the the two big
statues of uh Kim ilung and Kim
Jong Kim the the father and grandfather
their statue are there okay you go there
to the main Square in pongyang and you
shout you shout that Kim Jong-un is a
dictator down with Kim
Jong-un
dictatorship go and do that in pongyang
what's going to happen to you you will
never come back from
pongyang now imagine you go to Beijing
you go to tan men square and you say
over there down with Shin ping down with
the dictatorship down with this evil
Chinese Communist Party what's going to
happen to you you will never be seen
again this is what we mean by a
dictatorship okay in India you can go to
Delhi you can go to jant man you can go
to whichever part of Delhi you want you
can shout Modi is a dictator what's
going to happen absolutely nothing's
going to happen you can say anything you
want about Modi various politicians have
been known to say that Modi is this Modi
is that
people every day on social media say
Modi is this Modi is that Modi is a
dictator Modi whatever whatever whatever
what happens to them absolutely nothing
absolutely nothing there is no price
there is no cost to claiming that Mr
Modi is a dictator now go to certain
states of India I will not name the
states allegedly some states are like
that you go there and you say something
against the chief minister and see what
happens to you so where is the
dictatorship and where's the Democracy
you I think this is just logical right
what fear do people have that Modi is
turning into a
dictator where is the
dictatorship where's the one party rule
I mean people vote for the one party
there are a thousands of other political
parties in India people can vote for
those they choose to vote for a certain
party I mean that's that's called
democracy what dictatorship some people
claim that in India's Constitution is
under threat let me explain something to
you my friends and go and ask any
constitutional expert go and ask this to
any constitutional expert has India's
constitution been ratified by the people
of
India I'll tell you something the
constitution of India has never been
ratified by the people of India what do
I mean by ratified when a bunch of old
guys wrote the Constitution in the 1940s
after 1947 48 49 whichever year it was
when that bunch of old guys mainly wrote
the Constitution created this gigantic
book 500 plus pages did they ask the
people of did they give the people of
India a chance to vote on the
Constitution or not that do you accept
this constitution or do you not accept
this
Constitution that is called ratification
in any genuine democracy the
Constitution has to be ratified by the
people only then can it become a
legitimate constitution in India the
Constitution has never been ratified by
the people of India just like the
partition of India was done by a bunch
of people they decided what was best for
India similarly the Constitution was
imposed upon India like this so let's
not talk about saving the Indian
constitution like it's some book that
the gods have given us it's a man-made
document which has never been ratified
by the people of India it's been shoved
down the throats of the people of India
okay so let's understand what the truth
is and let's look at things logically
not emotionally and not not on the basis
of people's opinions there are certain
YouTubers who go around saying
Constitution is under threat and
democracy is under threat and Modi is a
dictator just take a look at the ground
realities where's the
dictatorship go and go and claim that
modi's a dictator go and say whatever
you want about Modi what's going to
happen to you absolutely nothing there
you have it
okay uh let us okay Guru Prasad Guru
Prasad says what's your opinion on the
death of the Iranian president is it
planned by the us or by Israel
look whatever has happened whatever
information is out there in the public
domain is there any clue in that
information that points towards the us
or Israel I have seen none so far I'm
not saying it's out of the question that
there may have been a foreign hand in
this I'm not saying it's out of the
question the there's always a small
possibility but do we have any evidence
that points in the direction in that
direction we have zero evidence that
points towards a foreign hand the
government of Iran has not made any
statements or any claims blaming a
foreign power in this matter so what
happened is that the president of Iran
uh Mr RI had visited aeran the
neighboring Nation would you like to
look at the map we should look at the
map of course so let's bring the map
on uh where is the map let's bring it
on so you should know about Iran because
it's our neighboring country temporarily
we have a artifici nation in between but
it's going to be soon gone so Iran as
you can see is in the middle of the
screen now right through the west of
India we have Iran and if you go to the
northwest of Iran you have aeran so Mr
RI had visited aeran and he was coming
back he was returning by
helicopter uh and it's a hilly terrain
out there and uh Iran also has a
province of
aeran uh yeah so that's where the crash
happened somewhere here
in the Northwest and the helicopter look
I've said this so many times okay that
helicopters are not uh especially
reliable you should avoid traveling by
helicopters as much as possible I don't
know why world leaders and important
people like to travel by helicopter it's
it's risky and this helicopter that Mr
RI and Mr whoever else the other people
were traveling in it was uh an old
helicopter it was not being serviced or
whatever license
by the original manufacturer it was
somehow being maintained I'm not sure if
it had GPS I I'm not sure it had it had
all the terrain avoidance mechanisms or
whatever and they were flying in fog in
hilly terrain and you know what happens
you know you get disoriented and if you
look at the images of the crash which I
will not put on the screen it looks like
a controlled flight into
terrain okay it looks like that which
means that the pilots were in control of
the craft but they simply didn't realize
is that there's Terrain in front of them
because of the hills and the fog and all
that that's what it looks like at First
Impressions obviously I am no expert
when it comes to plane crashes but I
have seen lots of images of plane
crashes and aircraft crashes and
helicopter crashes and this doesn't look
like um from from the crash site it
doesn't look like an aircraft or a
helicopter that had lost control that
that was no longer under the control of
the pilots it looked like something that
was flown into the terrain which means
that that uh they did not realize
there's a hill in front of them or
whatever so that's what it looks like to
me at first glance eventually the truth
will come out if it does okay and uh
from whatever I've seen it doesn't look
like there is a foreign hand but let's
wait for the Iranian government to make
its official statement about the cause
of the
crash uh that's all I have to say so I
will not make any baseless claims based
on zero data and information that maybe
some other country was behind this Iran
obviously has enemies we know that
Iran has enemies in the region Israel is
clearly an enemy because Iran says that
Israel has no right to exist the US is
an enemy because of historical reasons
I'll not go into that and there are
other enemies as well Pakistan is no
friends with Iran yeah Saudi Arabia and
Iran have had this very trying trying
relationship and and much more so yeah
but but there's no evidence that there
was a foreign hand behind this
geopolitical dub says will there be any
adverse impact on on the India Iran
relationship after the demise of the
president of Iran I don't see
any I don't see any significant impact
or any impact adverse or otherwise on
the India Iran relationship because of
the uh untimely and accidental death it
looks like of Mr RI okay we have to
understand something Mr RI was the
president of Iran it doesn't matter
who's the president of Iran okay in the
past You' had other presidents I can
name a few Mr rafsanjani was a pres was
the president at one point in time Mr
Ahmed NAD was president and so on so
on the president of Iran is not the
supreme authority in Iran the supreme
leader of Iran is a whole different
person the president comes way below
that the president of Iran is not even
the number two power in Iran okay Iran
is an interesting political system the
true power is the supreme ruler or
supreme leader of Iran and that
definitely is not the president so when
it comes to foreign policy Etc well you
know they have a foreign minister they
have President and it looks like the
president and the foreign minister are
in charge of this but actually the
entire policy and everything else is
determined from up high from the supreme
leader of the country so if the
president dies it's not big big deal I
mean it's a tragedy and it's a bit of
instability etc etc but at the end of
the day the true decision making and all
that is done by the Supreme Leader of
Iran all right so no adverse impact as
far as I
see Devan vas says I'm a high school
student going to UCL in London this year
why are most western academic circles
woke and any tips on dealing with it
while there first of all
all the best congratulations etc for
going to UCL in London look right now
when it comes to the cultural M of the
West when it comes to the entire
political all those sensitivities and so
on it's all being uh driven by the by
what's coming out of the US so in the
past let's say five seven years the US
has gone increasingly hard left and what
and we see this phenomenon which we call
wokeism it's it's all over the place now
wokeism and it's something that they
have been engineering the academics have
taken over the us see a bunch of leftist
marxist Etc academics took over the US
academic system the 1950s 60s onwards
60s onwards 50s was ay trying time for
them the Makari era but eventually these
leftists these lefties this these left
loonies were not really loonies they
took over the entire academic system and
they've got a strangle hold over it now
and uh
the
entire uh atmosphere in the academic
system is now very hard
left and valkism is emerged out of some
of this especially after the pandemic
yeah after after 2020 it became fully
mainstream and the U the UK the UK is is
one of the wasal of the US it's one of
the puppets the puppet state of the US
the US has four hardcore puppets okay
the it's part of the five eyes the US is
the main eye and there are five small
eyes who are the the satellites of the
US the satellite States that's that's
Canada the UK Australia and New Zealand
so the prime puppet is the UK even
Canada is a secondary puppet and it's
not really the UK it's London okay so
when it comes to the nation of the UK
it's a poor Third Rate Nation attached
to London which is a First Rate economic
Hub okay it's the it's the uh West's the
central moneya laundering Hub of the
West so the UK is a poor Third Rate
Nation attached to this First Rate
Financial Hub called London so London is
a satellite of the US which means that
the cultural sensitivity is academic
system Etc will be an echo a copy a
slavish copy of whatever is coming out
of the us so you that's what you will
see over there you will see the same
attitudes the woke attitudes you will
see strong anti-india attitudes
increasingly stronger anti-india
attitudes uh if you if you stand up for
your culture if you say that I'm a proud
Indian you're going to be ostracized
you're going to be targeted you're going
to see this so my advice to you or when
you go there is I mean look if you are a
very strong willed combative person go
ahead and take them headon take the bull
by the horns but if your objective is
just to go out there get an education
get your education and get your degree
just do it quietly benefit from the
system there may be some benefits in the
western look the Western academic system
despite all its ghastly flaws is better
than the garbage that is the Indian
academic system which makes which is why
it makes sense for lots of people I I
tell people who are wondering whether
they should go abroad or not I I tell
them go abroad go study abroad go work
abroad get the experience get get get
the money get everything and then if you
want to come back you can come back and
contribute to your country so I would
say that go ahead
uh get get the degree get whatever
education you need don't try and fight
the system there uh unless you're a
strong willed bullheaded person which is
good if you are but I I would not uh
insist on doing that so go there get
whatever benefits you can get from there
and then you can come back or do
whatever you like if you want to stay
there another 20 years do that amass of
money good amount of money and
experience and then you can come back
and contribute to the country so that's
what I would say so it you have to
recognize The Facts of Life the fact of
The Facts of Life Is that the Western
academic system is is is deeply woke
these days it is very hard left leaning
it is very strongly Hindu phobic okay
and and there's a subtle Hindu phobia or
sometimes over Hindu phobia and
definitely an anti-india sentiment Pro
Pakistan sentiment so you're going to
have to be prepared for this mentally
and deal with it accordingly
all right
okay t m says how would you reform the
Indian political
system I would turn it into a true
dictatorship a true monarchy that's what
I would do a meritorious dictatorship
you know dictatorship in which only the
Merit the most meritorious can reach the
top that's what I would do I mean yeah
you can have I mean India the birthplace
of democracy so it will be a hybrid
system you should have democracy at the
lower level so that people can elect
their own local Representatives who will
take care of taking out the garbage and
and ensure ensuring that there's proper
electricity and water supply and on
delivery of services and delivery
delivery of governance delivery of uh
law enforcement all of that stuff all
that should be taken care of the lower
levels and the people should vote for
the representatives there but at the
higher level it should be a different
system I mean that's what we always have
had in the country and whenever you look
at if you look at if you look back at
the past 5,000 years of Indian history
whenever India has done tremendously
well it's always been a dictatorship at
the top so that's what I would
do you could take what I said with a few
grains of salt if you if you so wish or
a few grains of pepper spice it up a
little okay Rohan says why do physicists
look down upon Engineers I've heard the
same from you as well it reminds me of
back and forth of Sheldon and how from
Big Bang Theory okay I don't know about
Big Bang Theory look mathematicians look
down upon physicists they they consider
physicists to be these physicists they
manipulate mathematical symbols like
stupid fools that's what they think so
the mathematicians think that they are
at the top then you have physicists but
among the physicists also it's a
theoretical physicists who consider
themselves to be the superior ones and
the applied physicists and all the the
the experimental physicists are like the
menial servants so to say in the
hierarchy in the class system or
whatever system you you want to call it
then below the the physicists of all
different kinds you have the engineers
who don't do any intellectual work they
simply take all these principles and
laws and they apply it in the real world
that is donkey work you see donkey work
is very very low very low and then you
have people who indulge in chemistry and
biology it's even it's even lower than
that so that's kind of the the
caricaturized cliche way of looking at
things look the truth is you need very
few theoretical physicist in the world
but you need tons of Engineers without
Engineers nothing
works okay so I don't know what you've
heard from me I'll tell you what engine
without Engineers nothing works so you
need Engineers the theoretical
physicists are the ones who think who
have their heads in the clouds okay a
theoretical physicist will stare out of
his or her window for hours in a day
looking outside and that guy or girl is
thinking that guy is working okay for a
theoretical physicist work means staring
out of the of the window six hours six
hours straight and then scribbling
symbols on the know whiteboard or
Blackboard and stuff like that that's
that's that's the kind of work they do
so they their head their heads are in
the clouds and whatever discoveries and
insights they g whatever discoveries
they make whatever insights the gain
they're going to be useful 20 to 50 to
100 years down the line not no no use
today okay but without those insights
nothing the the great technological
leaps don't happen but it's the
engineers who make things work so I
think everybody has an important place
in the entire scheme of things I don't
think anybody's higher anybody's lower
without mathematicians we don't do
physics right everybody is important but
they have their own different place in
in the scheme of things and without each
of these places nothing works so that's
how I see it there's no high or low up
or down but yes this is a I mean this
this is a humorous way of looking at
things you know there's a there's an
hierarchy unspoken of hierarchy in
things well maybe you're watching too
much of Big Bang Theory but yeah well
all
right Viv Kumar says what happens if
India and the US simultaneously reject
One China policy and recognize Taiwan as
a country look words and actions I
always keep emphasizing this what's the
difference between words and actions I
can say tomorrow that Tibet is a free
Nation but what what difference would it
make there are facts on the ground right
the facts on the ground is that China is
in possession of
Tibet so it's about it's
about diplomacy it's about uh
maintaining certain appearances and all
that it's about certain principles Etc
so the Chinese insist that everybody
should adhere to the one China policy
but they don't want to adhere to a one
India policy for example
so what happens if India says that we
reject the one China policy and and
Taiwan is a
country well the Chinese will take
certain actions against India they will
first of all put out this barrage of of
of
abuse and harsh diplomatic language and
then they may uh change some more maps
and they may rename some more cities of
India in in to Chinese names but at the
end of the day there's nothing much more
they can do they can try military action
but then they will obviously face
consequences so the point is that we
have a global order a global economic
order in which
everybody cooperates
economically and we want to keep that
going as long and as smoothly as
possible because India benefits from the
global economy which includes China
China is a major player China benefits
from the global economy that includes
the US which which is the largest player
the US also needs China in the global
economy they need China's cooperation
they need those cheap goods and whatever
from China so everybody needs each other
now we want to make this system as
smooth and and as as well lubricated as
possible so as far as possible we try to
pretend that okay we will we agree with
you and all that uh and and so on but at
the end of the day when when things go
really bad you can take certain
actions uh so the Chinese if you
remember they used to issue these uh
visas uh stapled visas to Indians who
came from arunachal Pradesh they would
not give an official Visa they would
staple a visa on on the passport that's
what the Chinese used to do so they have
all these all these things they do but
they are way more powerful than India
that's why India had to just quietly
accept that at the time I'm not sure the
Chinese still do that this stapled visas
if they still do then so the thing is
when it comes to the Dynamics between
India and China India is a nation that
is from the hard power perspective just
1/4th of that of China China is four
times as powerful as India roughly
if you add up everything you know you
know the economic strength the military
strength the nuclear strength and power
projection and blah blah blah all of and
much more you add all of that up for
India and for China you will see that
China is four times as strong as India
in terms of pure hard power Brute Force
but India is a rising growing economy
and China is not soow growing that much
anymore and China's long-term future
isn't great so there's all these
dynamics that come in in in into play
and all that so right now if if India
and the US both went ahead and
simultaneously said that we don't
recognize the one China policy in Taiwan
as a nation there's not a whole lot
China can do right now especially if the
US is also involved uh in addition to
India but I don't see this happening
what's the point of riling the Chinese
up keep your head down and work towards
growing your economy like then shopping
said hide hide your capabilities and B
your time hide and
B okay
Guru Prasad says why is modern art so
weird and it makes no sense so I'll tell
you what you go to a modern art gallery
in let's say some big affluent city in
India you know Mumbai Delhi high
class art galleries you go to London you
go to London you go to New York you go
to these places and you see Modern Art
it makes no sense you're right Guru
Prasad there'll be this Big C canvas on
which there are the splashes of color
and some scribbles and yeah there you
have it and the valuation is $3
million or if if it's in Bombay it's
like 13 lakh rupees for one you know six
feet by six feet square weird squiggles
and all that stuff why is it like that
why why why why why let me explain to
you see it's like
this
okay let's
say let's say that I'm a very rich guy I
want to save
taxes so what I'll do is I will
commission a painting by one of my
famous artist friends
okay so I'll pay this guy whatever
money and this guy will spend half an
hour drawing the squiggles and these
weird shapes and whatever half an hour
on the canvas and then I will ask my
other art critic friends to do an
evaluation of this painting and they and
this is my painting it's now in my my
possession okay because I commissioned
it I paid my artist friend $10,000 for
that so my I paid my artist friend
$10,000 for the for for this half an
hour of work now I own the painting now
I ask my my uh art critic friends to
evaluate the painting and they will say
that this painting they will come to a
consensus that this painting is worth
$10
million okay I paid $10,000 for it I I
must have paid my art art critic friend
some money for this and they gave an
evalu valuation of this painting as $10
million now I take this painting and I
donate it I make this donation to the
local Museum or or to the National
Museum or whatever so if I do this I get
a tax tax break of $10
million does it make sense
now I get a tax break of the value of
the
painting there you have it it's all
money laundering it's all tax evasion
through legal loopholes so that's one of
the reasons why our modern artist so
stupid it makes no sense and yet you
have all these weird paintings valued at
so much money when it comes to real art
real art real art is aesthetic it's
beautiful Van Go I mean if you look at
vano paintings my God they're achingly
beautiful that's something incredible if
if I have seen paintings by obscure
painters s the nobody remembers her such
incredible painting she us to make she
obviously okay you may not know about
her story she had
schizophrenia and so on the thing is
this that uh art is it lies the beauty
lies in the eyes of the
beholder and uh everybody sees art
differently but much of Modern Art I
think we can all agree is is garbage and
it it has probably something to do with
money laundering in tax breaks and all
that okay that's an interesting question
yes
okay tamn bashu says are the macedonians
and Romans genetically related let's go
back to the map let us go back to the
map so we're talking about the Greeks
the macedonians and the
Romans now the Romans are not see the
Roman Empire existed about 2,200 years
ago yes uh they fought the Punic Wars
then you had the rise of Julius Kaiser
Caesar and uh then there was like these
few centuries in which Rome you know
this this region that area that you're
seeing on the map they conquered much of
it all the way from uh the British Isles
much of Germania Germany uh they
conquered Iberia which is Spain they
conquered North Africa much of it they
destroyed Carthage and Judea and
Anatolia which is now turkey and Eastern
Europe th which is Western turkey etc
etc etc
and of course they conquered Greece
Julius Caesar personally conquered
Greece and since then Greece became
became a part of the Roman Empire now
the question is are the macedonians and
the Romans genetically related so the
Romans themselves were not a monolithic
ethnicity just not one ethnicity there
there a bunch of ethnicities that
existed in Italy Northern Italy southern
Italy Etc and even if you go to Italy
today there are so many different
provincial and dialects and languages
that people speak so it's not one
ethnicity but let's say Italy is just
one ethnicity Romans and then the
macedonians you would have to consider
them Greeks if you if you want to take a
very high level view of things so the
Greeks and the Romans there is obviously
their neighbors even today in parts of
of of Italy especially the Eastern
portion of Italy there are people who
consider themselves to be Greeks even
today in
Italy so they Neighbors First of all
there's this B There is a very small you
know piece of Maritime real estate the
estate the Adriatic Sea which separates
Italy from from Greece today it's
Albania historically it was Greece
Albania has a strong Turk Turkish
influence uh
so it is said that after the Trojan War
ended lots of uh Trojans and other
people they
escaped to Rome to to Italy and it is
believed if I'm not mistaken that remas
and Romulus were also descendants of
Greeks or something uh remas Romulus are
the mythical founders of Rome of course
it is named after Romulus who killed his
twin brother remas they were both raised
by a She Wolf Etc so I would say to I'm
going round and round but I'm giving you
some context actually it's not actually
just going round and round my point is
that these are very closely uh located
countries or regions
geographically and there definitely is
co- sanguinity and genetic uh Affinity
between these two populations and
especially if you look at the past 2,000
years after the Roman conquest of Greece
there was a significant intermingling of
the populations and eventually Byzantium
Byzantium which is Istanbul today's
Istanbul historically Co Constantinople
became the capital of the Eastern Roman
Empire after the Western Roman Empire
fell to Christianity there Western Roman
Empire never disintegrated and died
actually it simply transformed or
transmogrified into the Vatican Empire
the Catholic Empire and and the popes
became the Emperors the de facto
Emperors but the Western Roman EMP the
Eastern Roman Empire still existed in a
different shape and form it was bz
Byzantium the Byzantine Empire and even
during you
know at the end of the first World War I
think in ear in the late 1910s or very
early
1920s when Greek soldiers liberated
certain Islands from the Turks from
ottoman from from ottoman uh occupation
the people of these
islands they lined up at the beaches to
see these Greeks and the Greeks were
asking why what are you staring at us
for and these people were saying we
wanted to see what Greeks look like and
the Greek soldiers said what do you mean
you aren't you Greek they said no we are
Romans so they until until very recently
consider themselves to be Romans and
there's there's a whole lot more I mean
if you go to Turkey okay Byzantium there
is the city over here called
urum which used to be a Roman city all
these many of these cities used to be
Roman cities there is arid somewhere
here where is I can't find it right now
adrianople and so on so yeah there there
a significant Roman history over here
and and eventually the Greek and Roman
populations kind of became the same the
Greeks obviously would would be very
unhappy if I were to say that they have
their own very proud traditions and
rightfully so but yes genetically they
are South South European people not
quite white not quite white people yeah
so there is a significant amount of
genetic Affinity between the two peoples
okay um
Anand says I'm going to attempt Anand
says I'm going to attempt my last chance
of a government exam I'm very much very
much worried about what if I do not get
through the exam please suggest
something about how not to worry okay
I'll tell you what the best way to not
worry I'm I'm giving just a basic
princip General principle you're trying
something and you very much want that to
happen but if you want to worry less you
need to have plan B and plan C as well
okay if this doesn't work I need to have
a backup plan okay I'll do that and if
that doesn't work I need to have one
more backup plan which is plan C that's
the only way you'll be free from worry
otherwise if you only have one thing
that you are relying on then that's
going to give you a lot of stress lot of
tension lot of worry so I'm not sure you
have that and that's why you're worried
in that case I would say that look uh
life is long okay it's it's the
percentage of people that get through in
these government exams it's let's be
let's be realistic it's very low so I I
wish you the best but in case this
doesn't work out I would say that you
need to take some
time and work out alternate approaches
as to what to do in life that's that's
what you have to do so look I'm assuming
you're in your 20s which is fine which
means you're in you're in the early days
of your innings in life okay you you're
you've scored 20 runs you score 100 you
can score that one way or the other you
can do it with the reverse Fe regular
sweeps Square Cuts or by accumulating
singles whichever way you want to do it
right
so
so find other things also that you could
do in life if this doesn't work out
that's what I would say that's the
advice I would give you at this point in
time and of course you should do your
best should do your best I'm assuming
it's IAS or something that you're do
doing so yeah study hard hope it works
out but if it doesn't work out it's I'll
tell you that it's not the end of the
road when you are in this high stakes
exam situation it looks like if this
doesn't work it's the end of the road
for me it's the end everything is over
that's not the case okay these exams and
all they just one stepping stone to
something else and sometimes if it
doesn't work out it may actually be good
for you so uh that's what I can tell you
through a lot of experience okay I've
gone through all these exams and stuff
10th 12th whatever else and
looking back it was actually no big deal
okay so I'll say that uh even if it
doesn't work out there's a lot you can
do in life if you just apply yourself so
so all the best and don't worry so
much Rahul Gupta says what's your take
on New Caledonia so there's a situation
there's a situation going on in new
calonia I don't know if it's still going
on let's go back to the map
new calonia is this little nation in the
South Pacific region so let's find it
this long long Nation over here is new
cidonia okay it's it's an island and
it's got a couple more Islands
right
okay so new calonia so this island it
essentially comes under France under the
jurisdiction of France you can say it's
a French Colony some people would say
that and uh there's been some rioting
and stuff over there I'm not sure what
they've been asking for ETC what the
people want there why the riots are
happening I've not really really looked
into that I am aware that some rioting
happened there and there was uh kind
of emergency law emergency measures were
were imposed by the by the
administration uh I think they shut down
the internet they shut down social media
Etc because of uh and there was some
violence and some some arson some
rioting some people apparently
unfortunately lost their lives that's
what I know but what it is about and all
I have not really looked into it that
much it's definitely one of these French
colonies that still continue and I
believe that the French actually wanted
to give the nation Independence but
there were there were referendums in
which the nation said no we don't want
independence so you can't blame the
French for for still being in control of
in charge of uh this nation
that's the limited amount I can say
about this but yeah it's
interesting
okay honestly IDK says should I do a ba
a Bachelor of Arts in international
relations or should I do a ba LLB so one
is Bachelor of Arts in international
relations the other one is a Bachelor of
Arts in LLB means law right I
mean if I had a choice if I had these
two choices what would would I do look
if you want to make money you become a
lawyer okay if you're a lawyer good
lawyer and if you
can become a part of the right legal
system especially higher up you can make
a lot of money in
India so if you want to be financially
prosperous and stable and independent
and all LLB makes a lot of sense I'm
just saying be practical but if you
really are passionate about
international relations Etc then you can
do that but then what are the job
prospects you can become a college
teacher college professor University
teacher reader lecturer
Professor that's about it or you can go
and try and go get into the ifs which is
a very very small intake every year so
being a diplomat is really really really
really hard so I don't know what are the
job prospects when it comes to
international relations okay you can
either be a teacher somewhere or a
professor or lecturer or reader or
something assistant professor College
University level maybe what ever other
level or you could join a think tank and
become an intern and become a writer or
something so there's there's limited
scope for making money and being uh
reasonably prosperous and financially
independent and stable when it comes to
having a ba in inter international
relations but if you become a lawyer I
guarantee you money is there especially
if you're a good lawyer and if you make
the right connections and right friends
let's say so yeah from a realistic
perspective I would say money is
important boss without money there's
nothing in life people will say that
money doesn't buy you happiness I'll
tell you what poverty doesn't buy you
any
Joy so money money buys you Independence
not happiness then what you do with your
Independence is it it's entirely up to
you so yeah that's what I would
say Okay three where is it 3698 user
said says it just came out the news just
came out that there was one more river
behind the Nile which was used to
transport building materials okay we
talking about the EG we talking about
Egypt over here okay let's go back to
the map and the map is staring at the
South Pacific so let's reframe our
orientation we go to Africa Africa we go
to m we go to
Egypt okay we let's take a look at the
satellite image because that brings the
Nile out in stark contrast against the
desert so you can see this green long
green tongue
in the desert Egyptian desert and that
is the Nile River and obviously here is
the Nile Delta Cairo and if you come to
Cairo Al then you will see the Pyramids
of
Giza so there's three pyramids where are
these how do I locate where is
it I I I I where is Pyramids of
Giza okay I'm just going to do a Google
map
search okay to save time pyramids of
Giza where is it oh here it is we find
we find so there are three pyramids that
we are aware of and the big big big big
big gazillion dollar question has always
been how did the Egyptians ancient
Egyptians construct this gigantic
pyramids that's always been the question
take it out take it take a look at this
these are the pyramids pyramid of kfre
the Great Pyramid of Giza and the
Pyramid of men and there are smaller
pyramids as well pyramids of queens and
the question has always been how did the
ancient Egyptians construct these
gigantic
monuments
and and you will find people saying it
was all aliens because they don't have
any answer as to how was this done in
enormous monuments constructed without
electricity without modern technology so
now somebody I mean I I read this
somewhere a couple of days ago that
apparently this River the Nile there
used to be another branch of this
River uh which flowed somewhere around
here on the banks and in these pyramids
were built constructed on the banks of
this now defunct branch of the River
Nile and apparently all these transport
all these materials were transported or
by boats or whatever other mechanisms on
the river and apparently they discovered
the river its existence by doing some
surveys under the ground by using ground
penetrating radar or something like that
so that would be a very logical and
plausible explanation as to how these
gigantic building materials were
transported if there was a river that
flowed right over there then it was
would have been really easy to transport
so that kind of seems to answer the
question as to how the pyramids were
built but then the question arises that
how did the river flow in exactly the
right pattern that these three pyramids
they line up just like the sword of
Orion so if you look at
the con the constellation of
Orion okay then you will see that
Orion's Belt if you there are three
stars that make up oran's belt and these
three stars their Al alignment is
exactly the same as what the ancient
Egyptians made the alignment of the
three pyramids there so
yeah but yeah
maybe as long as the river flowed nearby
they could have been able to transport
the stuff and build the pyramids along
the or iation so it kind of if if this
is true if this news report is true I
still haven't seen the scientific report
but if the news report is true it kind
of throws a lot of light on how all that
gigantic Building Material was
transported and that kind of answers
many questions about the construction of
the Great
Pyramids okay vun Deon says when will
kiar come I really don't know I I mean
it's said that Kar will come one of
these days days and that will be the end
of K yog and everything will be fine
again Ki is the next Incarnation the
next Avatar of Lord Vishnu of Shri
Vishnu Well if I knew then I would be a
god myself wouldn't I I'm not sadly so I
I don't know when when it will happen
sorry Adit Singh says have you read the
book The Hunt for Red October and you
think that we may find ourselves on a
similar situation well I don't think I'm
ever going to be on a submarine I'll
make sure I never go on a submarine and
I don't like being 300 M under the ocean
you know in a metal tube so I probably
won't find myself in a similar
situation uh but yes I have read the
book long long long long long ago like
really long ago and uh very good book
they even made a movie with Shan conry
who passed away a couple of years ago I
mean reasonably recently one of the
great actors uh so it's about this uh
it's about this Soviet
submarine nuclear submarine that's on
petrol and it goes Rogue and the Soviets
are worried that it's that the captain
wants to defect to the US the Americans
are are worried that it's actually you
know it's it's it's going to set off a
nuclear attack on the US and so on so
that's the situation and uh there seem
if I remember correctly there's a mutiny
kind of situation on the on the ship and
uh the captain faces a mutiny there
there's danger that he will be
overridden
there could be a message to launch a
nuclear strike as well I I don't
remember the details but yeah so what
the the the plot the thing that drives
the plot or or the basis for the plot is
that when you are in a submarine under
the ocean on a long Mission with no
commun essentially no Communications
from with your base from because
submarines are deep down right under the
ocean
then when you receive orders and those
orders seem extreme like essentially
launching a nu Nuclear Strike what do
you do do you just blindly follow the
orders or do you use logic and try and
make sense of the order and something
tells you that something is wrong and
you don't carry out the orders and is it
ethical to do so is it wrong to do that
and so on so that's kind of the Dilemma
that uh submarine
captains find themselves in and India is
soon going to have if we don't already
have submarines on I mean nuclear
submarines on nuclear
Patrol ballistic missile
submarines and uh yeah so in the future
I I hope it never happens but Indian
submarine captains also I mean India
will have to develop devise a system by
which communication is done and the
right kind of orders are
given to uh the
submarines that are on patrol and there
could be in Patrol maybe in the Bay of
Bengal Maybe
somewhere else far away from from Shore
so yeah there are all kinds of uh things
you have to keep into consider take into
consideration let's say you have a an
Indian submarine nuclear submarine
ballistic missile submarine that is on
patrol in the Bay of Bengal now the Bay
of Bengal to us looks like it's it's our
neighborhood swimming pool right but it
is a tremendously large piece of
Maritime real estate let's say you have
a submarine over here and uh if it's
here and you measured the distance to
vishakapatnam that's almost 1,000
kilometers away so you are 1,000
kilometers away from your Shore
and and you receive an order that makes
it look like there there was a nuclear
attack on India and then you to
retaliate and you to launch a response
immediately so do you keep the captain
in charge of the decision or is there
some other way you would control the
submarine to launch a nuclear attack on
demand lots of consideration that that
have to be
evaluated when deciding how
to what sort of mechanism to use so it's
very interesting from that perspective
yes playing with codes says which is the
best geopolitics book for complete
beginners there is no best geopolitics
book from for complete beginners none
exists but I have a geopolitics course
and you can see the link in in the
description that is for beginners and if
you take that course it will actually
help you understand geopolitics from
first
principles and uh it's it's perfect for
absolute beginners actually so yeah
there's no book there's the course which
I eventually will turn into a book so
yeah
okay Fire and Ice says why does do the
Delhi Metro trains have flat faces why
not aerodynamic Peak heads like the rrts
V bat Etc well uh ideally you want the
train engines the Train the first thing
the front facing compartment to be
aerodynamically shaped but if the speed
if the maximum speed isn't that great
then it doesn't need to be very
aerodynamic aerodynamic effects come
into play only at high velocities so if
you have a train that travels at let's
say in excess of 120 to 150 km/ hour
then it really needs to be
aerodynamically designed shaped if you
have a train that travels too 50 km per
hour it needs to be shaped like a bullet
so that's why we we call those trains
bullet trains like the shin Canen train
trains in Japan the tgv trains in France
and Europe Etc but if you have a train
so I'm not sure what this the top speed
of the Delhi Metro trains is okay I I
have never used them I've never even
seen a Delhi Metro TR train station but
I'm aware it exists I'm not sure what
the top speed is I'm assuming the top
speed isn't great because I would assume
that you don't need such high speeds
within a city
itself and you may have lots of stops so
why why travel at 150 km per hour when
you have stops that are just 2
kilometers apart doesn't make sense so
when you have a metro system with lots
of stops each space separated maybe 2
kilm 3 km or so then your top speed
doesn't need to be that
high you may have a top speed of let's
say 60 70 80 km per hour for that you
don't need those aerody Dynamic shapes
so maybe that is the reason why that's
what I'm guessing I haven't ever spoken
to any engineer from the Delhi Metro I
haven't even seen the Delhi Metro but
I'm assuming because the top speed isn't
that great that's why you don't need
that aerody Dynamic shape but whenever
the bullet trains start in India you're
going to have those bullet shaped noses
which makes a lot of sense because
they'll be traveling at such high
speeds oh yeah we already took this we
already took that okay what's next
known one says what are the white spots
on
Series so now the question for most
people is is going to be what is cies so
let's go and uh it's it's it's an
asteroid uh let's go to Google Search
and take a look at the image of cies
okay so here we have it c r s it's the
largest asid that it's a dwarf planet
okay and as you can see it it rotates I
nice so you have this this bright spot
this bright white spot on series and
that's what uh no one is asking
about so uh I believe see I'm not going
to read any any of these articles I
assuming I I'm aware that this uh
existed most likely what the case is
that this dwarf planet may have a
subsurface ocean
of
water now if you have a crust and then
you have a subsurface ocean of water or
let's say if you don't have a subsurface
or ocean of water you may have ice below
the surface that's also another
possibility so let's say you have ice
below the surface and
you get impacted by another asteroid
another space Rock and that space Rock
its impact digs a hole into your into
into the Sur surface of of this dwarf
planet and that ice gets exposed then
when the Sun Shines on that ice on the
ice crystals it's going to be very
highly reflective that ice as we know
ice is a very highly reflective uh
material you've heard of snow blindness
I ice blindness right so that is because
of the high highly reflective property
of ice so maybe this bright spot could
be ice that was exposed because of uh an
asteroid impact
that's one possibility the other
possibility is that there is a
subsurface ocean of water which was
again exposed to the vacuum of space
because of an impact by an asteroid and
that froze
solid and now that ice is reflecting so
that is most likely the cause for the
white spots on series as far as uh I can
see I've not read the latest findings
and latest reports but it makes sense
logically and maybe you you guys if you
are interested you can if you're curious
then you can check it out I would highly
encourage checking out this stuff
because this fascinates me science and
astronomy astrophysics fascinates me
very
much rajat hatwar says why do the
southern part of why do people in
Southern India marry their cousins when
it's wrong in Hinduism and when they
know it's causing genetic problems oh
look look I don't
know uh I know that there is a this
tradition of co sanguinity co sanguinous
marriages cousin marriages Etc in
various parts of the world I think in
various parts of Europe you know you had
royalty that married their cousins and
all that you had uh I think in the
Islamic world it's it's pretty common
place I think the pakistanis are some of
the most inbred populations in the world
and in some parts of India also
apparently there is a cousin marriage
Etc
uh I think uh look in Hinduism I'm I'm
sure it's it's uh
we don't have any any any one book in
Hinduism right we have millions of texts
Hinduism isn't about one book Hinduism
is a library so I don't know everybody
has their own traditions and and local
Traditions I mean if you go to
India uh the food changes every 5050
kilometers the dialect changes every 50
kilometers the local customs and
traditions also change every 50
kilometers so I suppose in some parts of
India you still would have I mean you
would have
some such Customs like cousin marriage
which uh yeah well it exists what I what
can I say who am I to pass judgment
about whether it's right or wrong or
whatever we know from a medical
perspective from a scientific
perspective that marrying somebody who
is closely closely related to you is not
great because it's GNA there's a higher
likelihood of of having genetic defects
in The Offspring in the children so C
are pretty closely related right 1/4 the
same DNA
essentially um so yeah I don't know why
it exists but okay some people have the
traditions and who are we to question
them but yeah it's not great for the
genetic
lineages that's all I can say about
this Clash Cloud says what's a
carismatic personality how to develop it
well I wouldn't know I'm not charismatic
I think charismatic charismatic person
is somebody who Everyone likes or or a
very large number of people like like
somebody who is just you know very
attractive not just physically but as a
person as a through through their
personality traits one of the things I
think that goes into having a
charismatic personality is that you need
to be a very good
speaker you need to be able to command
people's attention when you speak you
need to have the gift of the gab and not
just smooth talking but you need to be
able to express yourself
powerfully and and uh
effectively so
essentially you need to be a great
public
speaker I think that is essential for
somebody to be charismatic and then you
also need to have some authenticity and
and some
some what would you call it some some
leaders leadership trait or something
that something that makes people want to
follow you and uh that makes people
trust you I believe yeah trust is
important uh charismatic people are
generally trusted by a lot of people so
yeah I guess all of that goes into these
are the different aspects of a
charismatic personality so I would say
that the core aspects
are uh you need a great amount of
conviction in yourself self-belief
secondly you need to be a great speaker
you need to be persuasive Ive thirdly
you need to be
trustworthy you you cannot be
charismatic if no one trusts you so yes
so I would say that these are some of
the factors that go into being a
charismatic person how do you develop it
first of all you need to be a person of
substance I know there are many Crooks
who are charismatic I would never
recommend going down the path if you
want to be a charismatic person do it
the right way and do and be a genuine
person of substance so first of all be a
person of substance yes you need to have
some really genuinely good
qualities some genuinely good uh
expertise of some kind in some some
field or the other and then you need to
be able to speak really well
convincingly and powerfully and you need
to be a trustworthy person and you need
to to be able to communicate that the
fact that you're trustworthy and people
should actually want to follow you so
all of that goes into being a
charismatic personality how do you
develop that I think it's through
self-development introspection
understanding your strengths your
weaknesses
and what you want to achieve in life do
you even have to be charismatic I mean
there are lots of people who don't need
to be charismatic let's say you're a
computer programmer as an example you
don't need to be charismatic let's say
you are a nuclear weapons developer you
you're a writer you write you don't need
to be charismatic it's only if you want
to be a politician or a military
commander or or something like that that
you would need to be charismatic or or
or an actor or an actress right right
apart from that you don't need Charisma
of course uh if you are charismatic
naturally or or through practice then
yeah you it helps your social life it
gets you it helps you get your thing
your work done and all that so from that
perspective yeah you may want to develop
a charismatic
personality so yeah I am no expert in
this I'm just
saying you know giving you a rough idea
that's
all
okay okay
Richard says I'm a Christian by birth
but after learning about the tactics
played by the French I'm confused about
my own religion I've always been loyal
to my Lord do you have any suggestions
for me listen I would say you have to
follow your conscience that's all if you
truly believe if you truly believe in in
the religion that you are born in then
you should follow that absolutely of
course we know that the problem is when
you get come to know the truth we know
what the french did in and we know what
the Portuguese did the what the
Portuguese did was even worse than what
the french did there was nobody as bad
as the Portuguese in India the manner
the means by which they converted people
to Christianity were horrific and they
used Christianity as a tool for for for
material wealth and gain I mean if you
look at the papal Bulls it's horrific
they they authorized these essentially
Pirates
to grab claim any any land in which you
had non-Christian people living there
and you could they were authorized to
take those people as slaves to enslave
those people and and divest them of all
their wealth and all their mineral
resources and everything and in India I
mean there was the Inquisition which
which uh Francis Xavier brought
into Goa and other parts of you know
that whatever lands of Portuguese had
grabbed and the methods were brutal
brutal brutal and if you go to Puch
Cherry places where the where the French
ruled there are big churches there that
were used that used to be
temples okay those temples were
destroyed and churches built on top I
mean these are facts I mean look up the
facts that's my point so once you know
this you're going to be conflicted if
you have I mean you you may pretend that
everything is fine but you can't lie to
yourself right so that's the problem uh
so I I would not make any personal
recommendations I would
say the truth is something you have to
discover for yourself and then you have
to follow your conscience as to whether
the the path you're following the
religious path you're following is the
right one for you or not do you truly
believe in it and it's a completely
totally personal choice that you have to
make so I would look I would not make
any suggestion the only suggest
suggestion I would make to you is to
study history that is why history is so
important important important it's not
about it's it's just about knowing what
happened because unless you know what
happened in the past you will not know
how the the world that we inhabit that
we live in came to be and there are all
these forces that were at play that are
still at play that are trying to shape
the world in in in in various ways for
their own personal benefits using
religion often and certain religions are
more enabled am enable to be used
politically and
militarily and at the end of the day you
to ask yourself what's the point what's
the purpose of religion the purpose of
religion
basically is to give you a moral
framework by which to live your life
whether you believe in God don't believe
in God is is a secondary matter but
being religious and following a
religious path means you have a moral
and ethical framework by which to live
your life so you don't have to think too
much now then you to ask yourself this
particular moral and ethical framework
I'm following is it really moral and
ethical that's what you have to ask
yourself and and the answer lies in the
chapters of History so all I would say
is is try and discover as much of the
truth as you can and follow your heart
follow your conscience that's all I
would
say Okay netian says will we um when
will we see nuclear powered vehicles it
would be almost forever lasting power
source
right um I think it was in 2019 that
Vladimir Putin declared that
Russia has a cruise missile that's
nuclear
power and that missile can essentially
fly for months without stopping maybe
even
longer so yes we already do have nuclear
powered missile I'm not saying missiles
with nuclear weapons in their Warheads
no not that the propulsion is nuclear
probably a nuclear
Ramjet so the Americans tested nuclear
ramjets I believe in the 1950s or 60s
maybe
1960s okay of an an airplane with a
nuclear power plant in
it and uh the nuclear reaction it heated
the air and and was the basis of the
Ramjet or Ramjet is
is uh it's essentially a supersonic jet
you can use a conventional chemical
fuels in ramjets but you can also have a
nuclear
Ramjet so yeah I think the Americans
tried it out tested it out and then they
abandoned the concept for various
reasons because they I mean you know
conventional fuels are much cheaper and
much readily much more readily available
and uh there's there's less of a chance
of nuclear fallout if the plane crashes
there's zero chance of of nuclear
fallout if the plane crashes but if you
have a nuclear power plant on board it's
going to contaminate a whole lot of a
whole large area and so on but yes the
technology does exist the Russians have
it they have missiles that have nuclear
propulsion probably ramjets and there
was this program in the 20th century to
have last Rockets like massively lar
large Rockets larger than today's
Starship you know SpaceX Starship larger
than that and those Rockets would be
powered by nuclear
explosions and that was designed to take
Humanity to Mars I think there is
a there's a documentary out there on
YouTube I Believe to Mars by a bomb to
Mars by a bomb check it out I think it's
still out there I'd seen it many years
ago uh I think Freeman Dyson was
involved in that in that project for
some time and then I think it was it was
demonstrated it its viability was
demonstrated but it was never taken to
the Rican conclusion because obviously
if you detonate nuclear weapons in the
atmosphere it's going to have nuclear
fallout and why do that let us stockpile
those nuclear weapons for a future
contingency right so yeah so the
technology isn't that hard to achieve
not that hard and when it comes to
submarines we have nuclear powered
submarines we know that right
a few Nations have nuclear powered
submarines uh but those essentially are
steam engines steam powered submarines
and in the Ste and the water is heated
to steam using the nuclear reaction in
in a nuclear reactor but nuclear prop
propulsion is a whole different story
but yeah it's it's very much feasible
even it's the technology already exists
but I'm not sure if and when it will be
actually
utilized abishek shrivastav says can the
US unlimited dollars look India can
print unlimited rupees if you want
Pakistan can print unlimited Pakistani
Rupees but why would you do that you do
that there's going to be tremendous
inflation the problem is that the
US the US has the world's Reserve
currency the US
dollar so what does it mean that the
that they have the world's Reserve
currency so there was this agreement the
Britain Woods
agreement I think it was 1940s sometime
just a year or so before the World War
II ended and in this agreement the US
was obviously the dominant power by then
they had demonstrated that so uh the
agreement was reached that the US dollar
will be uh kept on a gold standard and
the US dollar will be the world's
Reserve currency and everybody will
accept US Dollars whenever yeah whenever
needed and then this was enforced
through the US military Network across
the world power projection capabilities
that the us has so that's how the US
dollar became the reserve currency of
the world now what does it mean that my
currency the US dollar if I'm the US
what does it mean that my currency is
the world's Reserve currency it
means that if I
owe China a trillion dollars and I'm the
US I can just print a trillion dollars
and give it to China paper money or
electronic money it doesn't have to be
backed up by gold or oil or anything
people all around the world accept the
green backs the US dollars so I can
print a trillion of them and re repay my
debt to China if I have to but if I am
an African
country okay if I am an African country
let's say I am I am ner and I owe the US
$100
million then I will not be able to print
the $100 million because I don't have
the printer so I will have to trade with
other
nations I will to export uranium or
whatever it is my nation has whatever
resources and earn a mill $100
million in return and then use that
money to repay my debt to the US so I
will have to earn that money by giving
actual value to the Nations I'm trading
with you understand I'm going to have to
give actual resources to earn that $100
million but the
US so when ner or Botswana or South
Africa or Pakistan or Sri Lanka when
these nations have to repay debts in US
dollars they have to earn that money
first by providing actual value and only
then can they repay those debts but the
us if it owes trillion dollars gazillion
dollars Can it can it can just print the
money okay or do quantitative easing
like they say okay and give them money
and and that's the advantage they have
so yes they can essentially print
unlimited dollars and Export the
inflation to other
countries let's see how long this lasts
it's it's a Ponzi scheme that's what it
is it's a Ponzi
scheme okay prati V says why is the
global map shown in most places a
distorted version of the actual
geographical map favoring Northern
hemispheric countries okay let's let's
take a look at that let's go back to our
friend
Google and uh let us see what the
meranto projection
does okay where is Google here is Google
merant Mercator Mercator
Projection Mercator whatever so Mercator
so it see what the Mercator Projection
does is that it takes a sphere and and
superimposes it on a two-dimensional
rectangle a sphere is a
three-dimensional object the Earth is
not a perfect sphere it's an oblate
squashed out kind of sphere but it's
roughly spherical so you take this
sphere and you you distort it out of
proportion and you and you superimpose
it on a rectangular two dimensional
surface and and then what it does is
this so the truth is I'll tell you what
the truth
is you look at this okay let's just look
at this the truth is that
Africa is larger than the whole of
Asia from from east to
west Africa the distance between the
Eastern tip of Africa and the Western
tip of Africa is greater than the
Eastern tip of Eurasia and the Western
tip of Eurasia that's how large Africa
is or at least it's comparable roughly
comparable but if you look at it it
looks tiny green land looks gigantic
when it's
actually the size of roughly Sri Lanka
or something and and so on so the
northern hemisphere is made to look much
much larger and the nations of the the
the land masses of the Southern
Hemisphere look much smaller I'm not
sure if it is by Design I mean here yeah
here you can see how they've done it I'm
not sure if it's by Design because most
of the land masses that we know of exist
in the northern hemisphere but uh yeah
there are different ways of doing this
but it gives you a very
uh uh a distorted understanding standing
of the
world and it kind of favors the nations
in the northern hemisphere especially
the European nations especially North
America not sure if it's done on purpose
or if it's by Design or if it's just by
accident but it is what it is yeah so
that is that is what it is it's because
you're essentially attempting to
superimpose a threedimensional image
onto a two-dimensional surface
okay vitri marz says as the general
election is going on in India are we
noticing a serious amount of a surge of
foreign interference on social media
what can the do what can the government
of India do about this in the next term
look foreign interference is a fact of
life especially when it comes to the
West the West has is a past Master at
interfering in the internal affairs of
other countries there are only four
genuinely Sovereign countries in the
world which is the US Russia China and
India and even when it comes to these
four nations there is they are all
susceptible to foreign interference
especially the non- US countries the
non-western countries think about it
like
this the Western countries see unlimited
us interference in everything let's go
to the West okay um let's get rid of the
Pyramids of Giza okay so when it comes
to the Nations that are part of the EU
the European Union and when it comes to
the Nations that are part of NATO there
is unlimited us interference in their
elections in their day-to-day
functioning in their governance in
everything the E the great the the
largest and most powerful nation in
Western Europe is the US even though the
US is not part of Western Europe so
that's what they always do they they
control Nations like South Korea and
Japan and Germany and and and uh
Italy they have a tremendous amount of
influence and control in Africa as well
the Middle East is has
been what shall I say and so they want
to do that in India as well so they're
going to they have various ways of doing
it they can allegedly create artificial
political parties in India allegedly
okay they have networks of NOS in India
which receive funding for various
purposes like industrial scale religious
conversions and uh those religious
conversions are also the objective is to
control those converted populations and
make them do things that are against the
interests of their nation and so on and
then obviously there is social media so
you
you you can have various think tanks
that put out certain opinions about
India that that India's democracy is
backsliding that minorities apparently
are under under threat in India they are
oppressed Etc Which flies in the face of
every single fact that the world knows
then so that you have Think Tank think
tanks that do this then you have various
big Publications that that put out all
these articles which are kind of slanted
against India then you have Indian
origin professors and so on who will
weigh in with those distorted opinions
you know gangadin and the the the brown
coolies oh yeah I should not use the
word brown kolie right the term brown
I've already landed into
controversy once what's his name I
forget the guy's name okay forget about
him he's not important and then you have
various social media stars and
influencers who will say that India's
Constitution is under danger India's
democracy is is under threat and Mr Modi
is a dictator so yes there is this
multifaceted multi-pronged attempt
constant barrage of
propaganda and the objective is to
interfere in the electoral process in
India and to and to shape the narrative
and the opinion and the perception about
India on the global scale so what they
are doing see most likely if if things
go well Mr Modi wins okay I am I'm Pro
Modi let I mean I I make no no secret of
that I want Mr Modi to come back to
Power so hopefully if all things
everything goes well as is most likely
Mr Modi wins but these foreign Nations
these foreign powers they know that Mr
Modi is likely going to win with a big
margin what they're actually doing is
they are setting the stage for attacking
India and Mr Modi during Mr modi's
thirdd term okay because the West sees
India as as as an emerging
threat the West wants to control the
entire world they already made a big
mistake with China by aiding and
abetting China's rise and now they don't
want India to be the next China right
now India like I said from the hard
power perspective it's just 1/4th of
what China is China is four times more
powerful than India from a hard power
perspective but in 20 years time in 10
years time India will be a totally
different Beast if the economy keeps on
growing and they don't want that to
happen so they will do their best to uh
malign India so that India's economic
opportunities kind of
dwindle and they don't want India to
grow economically they will do their
best to H for India's economic growth
and so on and so forth so that's why you
see what you seeing and you're going to
see more and more of that as you go
forward okay there you have
it
okay okay let's see what else do we
have PES says why did Alexander the
Tyrant not face any resistance in Egypt
was the rush and were the other aan
kings cruel towards them that's a good
question my guy Tes has read some
history hasn't
he okay let's go to the map yes so
here's what happened so in the year what
year was it 300 and something 327 BC or
329 BC or look up the dates I don't
remember dates but somewhere around that
time Alexander the Greek Alexander the
Tyrant uh dictator of
Macedonia uh his father dies King Philip
and Alexander has suddenly is is thrust
into this position of of the inheritor
of the of the kingdom of his father
Philip his father is assassinated
essentially and the Assassin is killed
so nobody knows until today what was the
motive of the assassination was
Alexander's mother involved in the
assassination was Alexander himself
involved or was it somebody else we
don't know so Alexander becomes the king
and then he has to subdue various uh
Kingdoms in Greece itself he
devastates the city of what was the
thieves was it he sells half the
population into
slavery and then he he decides to carry
on with his father's plans to invade
Persia the old enemy and so then they
cross the the the ocean Over the agian
Sea and they cross over into Anatolia at
the time much of Anatolia was under
Persian control but the people were okay
with the Greeks coming in because the
region always oscillated between Persian
control and Greek control and the people
were mostly Greek ethnically so uh so he
takes he crosses into Anatolia he he
defeats the Persians in a battle
somewhere in Anatolia I don't remember
where it was and then he comes
eastwards and then uh before he goes
down south to Egypt he destroys the city
of Ty now where is Ty today I need to
find Ty Ty is somewhere in Lebanon here
it is the city of Ty so the city of Ty
used to be an island okay just a few
hundred meters of the coast today it is
all together but it used to be an island
and Alexander besieged the city and uh
eventually after several months he was
able to break the siege uh I mean I mean
break into the City and then he
Unleashed all kinds of barbarities and
atrocities crucified tens of thousands
of people and horrific stuff he did okay
entire and then he goes down south
into Egypt and what he finds is that the
Egyptians are happy to see Alexander
because they had been under Persian
occupation okay it wasn't daras the
first it was daras the third if I
remember correctly but I don't think the
Persians were especially cruel towards
the Egyptians or anything they were
simply a powerful Empire and they
occupied Egypt so the Egyptians kind of
saw Alexander as a liberator so
Alexander just walks into to Egypt Egypt
opens its gates to Alexander there's no
real battle or anything and Alexander
installs a governor in in Egypt his name
was
tmy and his descendants were the kings
of Egypt so that that's the beginning of
the Greek rule over over Egypt and other
Emperor Ashok he knew of toam I don't
know which toam it was the first second
third he called him Tula Taya anyway so
what happened is that the Greeks just
allowed Alexander to Walts in and take
the country the that's what happened and
then Alexander did only one good thing
in his life essentially he built a city
that the Arabs called alandria it is
called Alexandria the one city that he
built that still stands he has he
alleged to have built many more cities
we don't we don't find any sign of that
but this one city was built by him
apparently Alexandria
alandria uh so I don't think the
Persians were especially significantly
cruel towards the
Egyptians it was like you know when when
when the British took over Bengal from
sadullah Etc and the people of Bengal
saw the British as liberators because of
the because they were tired of the of
the rule of
sah so it was kind of like that but I'm
not sure if if the Persians were very
cruel or or heavy-handed towards the
Egyptians
not sure about that but very interesting
question over here it tells you that
they just has been reading history
excellent I like it good
job
okay um let's see some other
questions Prav Sharma says your opinion
on the true boundaries of akanda Bharat
okay what is akand bhat let's go back to
the map it's greater India historical
India look there are different opinions
and different versions of what akanda
bhat is uh so the thing about bhat India
is that India is not merely a nation
state today India has been recast since
1947 as a mere nation state by our
small-minded so-called Founding Father
so-called okay but India is not a nation
state historically for thousands of
years India has been a civilization
State and when it comes to India's
civilizational Outreach and India's
civilizational uh umbrella India civil
civilizational footprint it goes all the
way across Asia China has been deeply
deeply deeply influenced civilization
and culturally by India so has Japan so
has Korea the whole of Southeast Asia
going from brah madesh Myanmar to swabi
Thailand to Laos Vietnam Cambodia Etc
and Indonesia obviously the majapahit
Empire Indonesia's golden age was its
Hindu Hindu Kingdom Empire the majapahit
Empire then you had Champa obviously the
so-called South China SE is actually the
Champa SE the Champa were all Hindus and
the cholas obviously had the had their
Conquest all the way to the Philippines
the Spanish destroyed Hindu Philippines
they they converted the Filipino people
to Christianity and they destroyed the
system of the Filipino rajas and
Philippines were called maharic at the
time and they used to have Sanskrit
inscriptions and they were all Hindus
and that was destroyed so if you look at
akand bhat and if you look westwards
obviously gandhar was part of bhat which
is Afghanistan the true border of India
westwards is the border with
Iran the border of Afghanistan and
Pakistan with Iran that's the true
historic border of India westwards and
during the time of Shir chingis Khan the
borders of Tajikistan were the borders
of India so India and Tajikistan shared
borders during the time of Shir chingis
Khan okay and there is this gate over
there the Gates of Hell or whatever they
call it the hot Gates or something they
call it uh which was kind of the border
between Tajikistan and Barat and
northwards you we just gave this upet
was very much part of our
civilizational uh zone of
influence we never conquered or occupied
Tibet but Tibet was always culturally
and still is culturally Indian whichever
Tibetans are still left so if you look
at akand BH from a civilization
perspective is it's a much much much
larger area if you go back 2,000 plus
years the whole of Central Asia was you
know you had temples viharas stupas all
over the place all of Central Asia all
the St kazakistan Tajikistan usbekistan
so and so forth you had Hindu temples in
aeran and Armenia okay 2,000 years ago
more than 2,000 years ago and well I
will not say that Iran is part of
Greater bhat because India is not Iran
was an Empire 3,000 years ago the hakam
Manish Empire the AED Empire uh but yeah
India's civilization footprint is very
very very wide and let's not even go
down south to Africa and all that
because tremendous Indian influence
there as well but if you want to Define
what is akand Bharat as a civilization
State entity I would not today want to
include Indonesia even though culturally
they are well our our
cousins but I would say Myanmar would be
part of it you know in 1935 the
burmes they voted to remain part of
barhat they did not want a separation of
Burma from India but the British
nevertheless went ahead and forcibly
separated Burma from India in 1935 the
had voted not to separate from
India nobody teaches you this none of
your great history teachers your eminent
historians or your textbooks will teach
you this that Burma had voted to not
separate from India in 1935 so there are
different definitions of akan Bharat Etc
today bhat is what it is today bhat is
not even full bhat forget about Pakistan
Afghanistan the the map that we have the
official map we don't even control all
of that some parts have been bitten off
by other countries we will get that back
in due course of time don't worry but
it's going to take time so
patience
okay all right what what see listen how
many how many times I take the same
questions okay I suppose some of you
have come in just recently this live
stream has been going on for 90 minutes
so yeah once the live stream is done you
can go back and look at the questions
I've taken many of the questions that
are being asked right
now all
right okay MRI says please throw light
on the intellectual migration of German
scientists during the post World War II
period especially Verner Von Brown who
contributed to American dominance and
Science and Technology the Americans had
this uh something called Operation
Paperclip in which they offered blanket
am amnesty to all the top German
engineers rocket scientists Etc and they
shipped them all forcibly to the US so
Verner Von Brown he was Germany's
greatest ever missile engineer rocket
engineer designer whatever you want to
call it and he at the first opportunity
with his brother I believe surrendered
to the US to American soldiers and uh
they shipped him to the US they the
Americans got hold of as many rocket
Parts Etc missile Parts Etc as they
could and shipped them off after the us
as well the Germans were the P ver Brown
okay he was the pioneer of not just the
first world's first cruise missile but
also the world's first ballistic
missile the V1 or V2 V2 was the the
ballistic missile the the cruise
missile and V1 or whichever one was the
first ballistic missile so the Americans
got their hands on all these rockets and
on the main scientists shipped them off
to the US and they were essentially
uh kind of under detention okay but
eventually Veron Brown became the head
of
NASA he never looks very happy in all in
the pictures that you see of him he
knows that he is there well is kind of
under detention kind of not really free
to go I think after he reached the US I
don't think he ever went abroad I may be
wrong but I can't recall any I don't
have any memories of him of of seeing
any of his activities outside of the US
after he reached the US and he became
the head of NASA eventually Verner and
he developed the Saturn five rocket
which took human beings to Mars to to
the Moon not Mars uh the the most
powerful rocket ever for of its time and
only eclipsed recently by the SpaceX uh
Starship and so on so it was not just
one brown but others as well and the the
Russians also had their own program of
of getting as many Russian German
scientists rocket Engineers Etc as
possible but the Americans got the best
of the lot and the Russians got whatever
is left and the American space program
was entirely based on German rocket and
missile technology and it was entirely
done by German rocket scientists and
engineers and the Russian space program
was once again entirely based on the
German rocket program rocket and missile
program and over there too the initial
main scientists and Engineers were
Germans and then you have people like
corev Etc who did their own thing and
then the Russians the Soviets
transferred one of their Rockets the
technology to
China and the basis for that also was
German
technology so the US
Russia USSR and China they they have
space programs that are based on German
designs so the German Space Program
rocket and program was the Genesis The
Fountain Head of the American Space
Program the Russian Soviet space program
and the Chinese space program it's India
and Japan that have developed completely
independent space
programs all these others have just
ripped things off but yeah there's
nothing wrong with it why reinvent the
wheel when you have a wheel you take the
wheel and you make it better there's no
nothing right or wrong about it it's
actually smart to just copy and and
iterate and improve all that so yeah
that in in short or in long is the
deal aayush Pand says recently rajat
Singh said that India will build six
aircraft carriers I highly admire
submarines yeah you've been listening to
me have
you uh submarines are the principal ship
of the 21st century is this a good step
look as far as I know he has made a
statement
look I can say that I'm going to develop
27 spacecraft by by 2040 me personally
doesn't mean I'm going to be able to do
it or maybe I or that I want to do it
but you can make certain statements you
don't have to walk the
talk
so um as far as I I see it it's a
statement maybe there could be one more
in the
offing but six aircraft carriers if if
let's say conservatively one aircraft
carrier will cost let's say five or6
billion dollar in today's money let's
let's be conservative and let's say it
just cost $5 billion
okay so if you want to have four
more we have two right now that's $
billion imagine how many submarines and
other scary things you can buy with 20
billion so do you really want to spend
$20 billion on on this in incredibly
concentrated lethality which is a
tremendously enticing and visible Target
slow moving Target yeah it can defend
itself with aircraft and all that but
come on in today's world we have seen
how cheap technology can defeat the best
systems look at what's happening in
Ukraine look at what the huis are doing
and so so my point is I don't think
we're actually going to build six I
think they'll probably make one at least
one more at least uh I wish that money
was used for or deadlier and scarier
assets like like submarines even cheap
assets like like missile boats which can
be really deadly I mean look at what we
did to Karachi in 1971 with with these
cheap missile
boats missile boats can be can be really
really effective and they're really cost
effective put three brahos missiles on a
on a $ 2020 million you know Heap vessel
and see what damage it can do uh and so
on so my point is I'm not sure that this
will actually happen I am not a look if
you have a gazillion dollars to spend
then by all means have 20 aircraft
carriers I I have nothing against
aircraft carers personally my point is
we have limited resources and the what
we have to do is to optimize the use of
these
resources so are we a nation that has
tremendous power projection capabilities
right now no right now we have holes in
our coastal defense we don't have
sufficient submarines
we don't have tremendous numbers of
Warships like the Chinese do know cheap
disposable warships first build up the
ability to to safeguard your coasts and
have no holes there then you build power
projection capabilities incrementally
and you already have two aircraft
carriers so if you want to spend money
because you need the prestige have one
more but yeah you need submarines
submarines are the scary stuff
submarines are invisible you don't see
them and they can do tremendous damage
yeah you have technology the the
magnetic anomaly detectors and whatever
else but subm Marines are scary but
anyone okay and they can do tremendous
harm to the best of the
vessels so I would say submarines should
be a priority and we don't have enough
submarines I mean North Korea has three
times five times I don't know how many
times more submarines than us you know
they may not have the best submarines
but they have quantity and like Jose
said quantity has a quality of its own
you have enough numbers of cheap stuff
it's going to make a big difference you
take a aircraft okay cheap aircraft Mig
21 class not the Mig 21 itself which is
obsolete but something which is new and
of that ability of that
capability and let's say one one of
these aircraft costs you $15
million which is peanuts in today's
money okay from the military perspective
and why not build a thousand of those
I'm just giving a St stupid example okay
just to illustrate my point so if you
have 10 it's $150 million 100 means 1.5
billion a th000 means 15 billion for $15
billion you get a th000 fighter playes
imagine what difference it
makes even though they are cheap and
kind of obsolete you've got a thousand
of those and you should you should see
the speed and acceleration that Mig 21s
have or aircraft of of that class has
scary scary stuff so even today a
thousand of those would make a gigantic
difference and people would be scared of
you so quantity has a quality of its own
so I would say instead of concentrating
your lethality on these giant
shipes distribute The lethality in an
invisible and widespread manner that
makes more sense from my perspective but
obviously I am no expert and I don't
have the military rank so who am I to
say
anything all
right uh
the way Krishna says which all nations
in India's neighborhood should we have
strong relations to control Indian Ocean
region we don't need great relations
with anybody to control the Indian Ocean
region I'll tell you
why India bat occupies this God gifted
position in the Indian Ocean region this
position gifted by the gods okay look at
the the short the distance from here to
here it's almost 2,000 kilometers we are
jutting we are projecting 2,000
kilometers down south into the Indian
Ocean region and from there India can
dominate the entire region if only India
were to build the capabilities the naval
capabilities a ton of submarines and a
ton of of ships with long
legs and missiles and a couple of
aircraft carers thrown into the mix
because we already have those you have
that you can project power all across
the place the sky is the limit you can
project power all the way to Antarctica
if you want and of course it helps to
have friends so we have friends we have
good friends in
France the French are our friends
reuno both MAA is macious of course but
Runo is French and the French have other
assets over here as well so macius has
this island called agala which I will
not show you if it is not okay and we
have another friend in the SE shells so
we have good relations with and seal and
I I'll leave it at that we also have
good relations with the gulf Nations uh
the UA is pretty happy that India is
doing well okay the UE is a good nation
good friend to have Oman is a good
friend to have you must have heard of
the port of dukum or maybe you've not
heard of it but that's all
right and uh Singapore is a good friend
Sri Lanka it's always good to have good
relations with Sri Lanka and uh
Thailand Myanmar banglades of course so
I think we should have good relations
with everybody as far as possible some
of these nations are incorrigible like
Pakistan well those are temporary
Nations so it's just a matter of time uh
maldis will will learn the lesson soon
sooner or later but overall I think
India is a non-threatening nation a
non-hegemonic nation Nations like the
UAE Etc they know that India is not
going to turn up tomorrow morning with
like 20 ships in their in their
territorial Waters it's not going to
happen India is not that sort of nation
so they're actually inded and happy
about the fact that India is playing a
more active and uh pronounced role in
Freedom of navigation operations Etc in
the region like in the Gulf of Adan
anti-piracy operations of the coast of
Somalia Etc so U yeah so India is
already doing a good job diplomatically
and from the international relations
perspective to have good and strong
relations with a number of nations in
the region Indonesia as well even
Australia is nowadays A friend of
indias you guys you may not remember the
days of the 1990s when Australia had a
very different attitude and approach
towards India so yeah so we have good
relations with many countries and it
always helps to have friends why
not gai but says when is Dr NJ R's paper
coming out I'm not sure I'll have to
speak to him and ask him it's been a
while but you know that's the process in
science you to do it step by step
systematically you have to follow the
due process and all that and eventually
you get the result so
I'll need to speak with him and maybe
next time I'll tell you what the
situation
is all
right B says why is the biggest genocide
in known history the Hindu Holocaust
ignored by the whole world Will trump
build a Holocaust Memorial for the
Hindus Pakistan is a fake Nation with
brainwashed people look first of all
trump it is not Trump's business to
build a memorial a Holocaust Memorial
for Hindus the Hindus are not Trump's
people Trump doesn't serve Hindus so why
would Trump do that it's not his
business it's not his problem the
problem is
us the the number one thing is this that
there are no statistics there is no data
I mean the the Turks and the oppress the
the Invaders and occupiers who came to
India and do all this Devastation and
genocide they actually recorded
everything so some historians need to
sit down and go through all these
records and
add everything together tally everything
up how many lives were lost how many
people were massacred how many temples
were destroyed how much wealth was taken
out all of that needs to be talled put
together it's just accounting some
somebody needs to do that somebody with
the patience and the and the discipline
to just sit through waigh through all
this data and add it all up but nobody
wants to do that and our so-called great
eminent historians Court historians they
have willfully and deliberately stayed
away from the subject so none of the
known books mentions a Hindu genocide no
academic research paper talks about
Hindu genocide so then everybody can say
what what Hindu genocide nothing
happened tell me show me a book show me
a research paper about Hindu genocide
and if you try to write a research paper
it will never get published in a western
journal or even in an Indian Journal so
that's the kind of thing that's happened
they've created a system which denies
what happened so it can be rectified by
the Indian government but maybe now is
not the time that they want to do it
whatever so it's going to take some
some concerted efforts and actions by
Indian historians and Indian publication
public publishing houses to bring these
facts forth there is no doubt that the
worst genocide in human history was the
Indian genocide the Hindu genocide which
started about a thousand years ago more
than thousand years ago in Sy
then the first region to properly really
fall to the to the occupiers Invaders
the Turks was gandhar Afghanistan and
then we know what happened and if you
put all the numbers together you add up
the turkic genocide and turky genocide
in the Christian genocide which is the
British and Portuguese and all the
genocide I think the the figures will be
horrifying over 500 million now some
Geniuses with with huge IQs will say but
India's population was 300 million how
can you say 500 million
died so for them I would say please
learn some simple math and T the
population births and deaths over a
thousand years period and then you will
see a different sort of figures that
will turn up but you need a little bit
of brain cells to understand
that okay yeah so that's the
deal Joseph peda says which system is
please better for family structure
patriarchy or matriarchy in a society
thanks um he's very controversial topic
you see uh look
uh it is known that the US is now
becoming a matria female dominated
society and uh most kids grow up in
single parent families which are
typically single mother families
so most children grow up with one parent
and that parent is a mother now
statistically it is known it has been
demonstrated in the US that if a child
grows up in a single family single
single parent household and that parent
is a
father then the child has a much lower
likelihood of being depressed when they
grow up or being an alcoholic or being a
criminal means going to jail but if the
same child or but the children who grow
up in the household of a single mother
are much more likely to be alcoholic or
much more likely to be depressed when
they grow up with they adults and much
there's a much higher probability of
them being Inc
incarcerated for
crimes so from all that data which is
relevant to the social social conditions
of the US it looks like single father F
families are are superior to single
mother families so that's the limited
information that we have from that
perspective and overall if you look at
it globally most societies have been
patriarchal societies it doesn't mean
there's inequality and women are
oppressed that's feminist feminist
nonsense okay it doesn't mean there's
oppression of women and women are
marginalized and all that it means that
the genders have different roles now
they they say oh my God you're talking
about gender roles how dare you talk
about gender roles there are no gender
roles everybody should do the same
should do
everything that's all fine but look
human history is 100,000 years old at
least Homo sapiens and
historically whatever evidence you see
is is all matriarchal systems there are
very few matriarchal societies the chos
islands were a matriarchal society which
the Americans and British destroyed the
chos islands here so-called British
Indian Ocean territory completely
illegal occupation this was matriarchal
society which was destroyed by the
anglos then you you have some
matriarchal Societies in Kerala some in
uh Northeast India far the Far East of
India and so on but that's that's a big
Rarity most societies are patriarchal
historically have patriarchal India
10,000 years old civilization minimum
has always been overall a patriarchal
society and women had a great role to
play in this so I
think all of this has evolved over time
and Society evolves through natural
selection again so whatever is best for
society is is the system that is
followed so maybe from that perspective
patriarchy seems to be the best
I'm just
saying okay Tas says there's a giant
lake lake formed by a meteor yeah impact
at lunar in Maharashtra could that be
the reason behind the formation of the
Himalayas and other mountain ranges can
meteors uh cause a shift in teonic
plates okay let's go to the map and find
this uh creater lunar
lake so here it is in Maharashtra let's
zoom out first and see where it is
located okay it's it's in Maharashtra
okay lunar Lake now let's zoom in zoom
in zoom in where is
it
ca all right let's zoom in yeah we are
so this is lonar Lake and as you can see
it's it's it's circular Lake and this is
the the result of a meteorite impact and
this impact happened about if I'm not
mistaken some 30,000 years ago or so so
the
Himalayas started
forming about 50 million years ago and
the lonar lake happened was formed about
30,000 years ago if I'm not mistaken
shall we just just double check it okay
let's go to our friend Google and and
find out how
old uh lonar lake is where is
Google I'm so sorry once again I put the
map on the
screen Google GOOG gole come on Google
Okay so let's let's see how old lunar
lake is
so as always we must not uh
Believe Wikipedia whatever it says
everything it says but for the sake of
brevity let's just look at what
Wikipedia has to say okay so how old is
this how old is this how old is this how
old is this 22nd July 2020 no no no this
was designated
okay okay so about 50,000
years or 570,000 years so it's between
half a million years and 50,000 years
old okay so the the oldest is half a
million years at most it is half a
million years old 5 70,000 years old but
the Himalaya started forming 50 million
years ago way before lonar Lake ever
existed okay so that that's why it's
clear that the lunar Lake the the impact
meteorite impact that that form the
lunar lake is not responsible for the
formation of the Himalayas now the major
question you're asking is that can a
meteoroid impact or asteroid
impact uh you know affect the movements
of tectonic plates and and create and
cause cause mountains to be formed well
we know of a few major meteor impacts
let me give you some examples let let's
go back to the
map so
uh here's the map once again let me go
to Canada for example you go to
Canada and there is something called the
managan lake now where is manik Kuan
Lake it's a gigantic piece of real
estate is it
here so what is this called this is a
different one this is via shakim but
this is also two meteor impacts and
these are two meteor impacts that
happened at very different times but it
looks like it's the same event because
they're right next to each other but no
it's not the case now where is managan
managan is here this is Lake
managan managan this was also the the
result of a meteorite impact so as you
can see the Earth has taken lots of
meteorite impact there was one massive
ginormous impact that happened in the
yukatan peninsula in
Mexico and there's a town There's a
village called Chik shub somewhere
here um where is chi chub has be
somewhere here which is kind of at the
epicenter let's just Google it quickly
instead of searching for it in the dark
chick
lub here it is is here
so this is essentially like Ground Zero
of that meteor impact and there is a
crater that's buried underground half of
it is under the ocean more than half of
it is under the ocean it's a a crater
with concentric circles and that impact
happened 66 million years ago and it was
the impact that contributed to some
extent to the extinction of the
non-avian dinosaurs so that event impact
event the chick shulu impact event threw
up Mega tsunamis super tsunamis that
were like 2 kilometers high and uh they
definitely caused the entire crust of
the earth to vibrate and uh it
definitely affected tectonic
activity and you had bigger impacts in
the past as well so when you have a
gigantic meteorite impact asteroid
impact or comet impact it's going to
affect plate tectonics it's going to
create volcanism on the opposite and end
of the planet
possibly and even the same end of the
planet because magma will come out
because it's ginormous impact but it
won't throw up mountains it won't create
mountains it will cause massive
earthquakes like you've never imagined
before earthquake like 15 on the RoR
scale I'm just guessing Okay it's a
logarithmic scale so maybe not 15 maybe
12 or
something uh but yeah so it will
definitely uh depending on the size of
the meteorite that's impacting the earth
and the velocity with which it impacts
if it's let's say a 10 kilm diameter
meteorite
asteroid like the chick shulu impact
it's going to cause it's going to cause
enormous damage to the Earth it's going
to affect tectonic activity it's going
to change the climate for a decade or
two decades it's going to cause a mass
extinction but it won't cause the
formation of new mountains and mountain
ranges all
right
okay what else do we have what other
questions do we have
endan says mugal Muggles mugal destroyed
the great native classical dance forms
and classical music system from Gujarat
Sy Maharashtra Rajasthan Bengal Kashmir
why no research done on this topic I I
wonder why no research is done on these
topics I I I'm I'm I find this topic
fascinating dance culture art
music and I've even done podcasts with
uh a few uh notable people from the
field of dance and
culture uh so I find this topic
interesting really interesting really
fascinating we need to know about this
entire musical systems dance systems Etc
have been wiped out and almost nothing
is left only folk dances are left in in
Rajasthan Sy s nothing is left not even
folk dances Gujarat you have folk dances
in Rajasthan you may have some folk
dances Bengal I don't know what B is
left
so yeah so much has happened it was
cultural genocide but nobody has
bothered to document this it needs to
happen needs to happen so yeah I I
really appreciate this question I agree
with you that research should be done on
this
topic so I'll take this question again
because I'm getting this all the time I
answered this as the first question the
first answer I gave in this live stream
was this but let me just take it again
my opinion about the sudden sudden
accidental death of Iran's president is
that look based on the information and
data that we have it looks like
controlled flight into terrain which
means the pilots were apparent it looks
like they were in control of the of the
helicopter they just didn't realize that
they are heading towards a
hill from all the information that's
available in the public domain I have
seen nothing that makes me suspect that
there was some foul play now may I'm not
saying I'm ruling out the possibility
that something may be am Miss I'm not
ruling out the possibility that some
other Nation may be involved or maybe
somebody within Iran may be involved the
possib possibility exists but I have
seen no evidence that points in that
direction Israeli intervention us
intervention some other power struggle
within Iran all kinds of theories exist
but what we have seen is a helicopter
that that essentially just flew into the
hill or the mountain in extremely bad
weather fog and clouds and all that and
it was an old helicopter it was not very
modern and very well equipped and so on
and helicopter are inherently dangerous
I've said this so many
times uh so from what I see I don't see
any evidence of Foul Play obviously I
have I have not been there and I'm not
investigated myself so I don't know I
have only seen the news reports and some
some grainy video and some images that's
all based on that I cannot conclude that
there's any Foul Play or other nations
involved possibility is there but proof
zero so yeah can't can't speculate and
make and and jump at conclusions in the
absence of of Hard Evidence one way or
the
other
okay shean ping me the pool ni ni sir
ni uh so why are billionaires funding
vois what's the real and endgame and
long-term impact of wokeism on global
societies uh well if if certain
billionaires are funding ISM it means
they're part of a larger agenda okay
that's what I can speculate I don't know
because I don't have the information I
don't know them personally it looks like
there could be a larger agenda and
that's why they are part of this what's
the long-term end game the long-term end
game is to transform the entire world
into a monoculture a monoculture and
atheistic monoculture which means that
the only religion is bism you don't
believe in God anymore we you don't have
any religion anymore which means you
have no moral compass or ethical
framework by which to live your life
which means that there is no right there
is no wrong and whoever is the influence
itial voice is going to tell you what to
do and whatever they say is right
there's no right no wrong there's no
evil there's no good you just follow
your heart's desires and your physical
needs and all that so it's all about
materialism consumption on all that and
that essentially uh is great for the big
corporations that want to make money so
the long-term impact of vocalism if it
just keeps on going it will destroy
societies it will destroy culture it
will destroy civilization and reduce
human beings to zombies or to put it
better slaves of the big
Powers that's what could
happen
Okay sov Kumar Pak says how was the diet
of ancient Indians different from
Indians today let's think
about ancient Indians means we're
talking about 5,000 years ago right we
don't
know I mean we may have some idea but
let's not talk about that let's talk
about Indians 300 years ago our recent
ancestors only 300 years ago so if you
go back to so today's 2024 right we
talking about
1724 which is uh at the end of the
so-called mugal Empire and when the
maratas were coming back coming into the
ascendancy and liberating India from the
foreign
occupiers at that time what was the diet
of India like this is before the
hundreds of artificial famines the
British
created so at that time I imagine that
the diet of Indians was much more
protein Centric than what it is today
today's di diet today's Indian diet is
the consequence of two centuries two and
a half centuries of
starvation so it's very
carbohydr carbohydrate Centric you go to
any restaurant for breakfast let's say
whether it's North Indian restaurant
food or South Indian food or whatever
East Indian West Indian it's all going
to be
carbohydrates if it's a south southern
Indian food it's going to be idlies and
dosas and medas and dalaras and whatnot
all
carbohydrates you go to a North Indian
restaurant it'll be CH Puri it will be
patas and whatnot all car carbohydrates
and some Dairy and similar similar stuff
it's all carbohydrates carbohydrates is
starvation food when you are dying of
starvation you want carbs because you
know that's it's a quick source of
energy so dals and all that stuff but I
would imagine that before the era of
starvation forceable starvation that the
British impos on India India's the
people of India would have had a very
different
diet so the diet which we think is part
of our culture and tradition is what
what was what our ancestors had to adopt
to ward of
starvation but unfortunately none of our
ancient cookbooks or things survive
because of the destruction of our
libraries otherwise we would have clear
evidence of what our ancestors used to
eat what kind of diet they used to have
I am more interested in the
macronutrient breakdown of the ancient
Indian diet of 300 500 years
ago if you if you ate a 2,500
calorie uh diet per day let's say then
what percentage came from fats what
percentage came from carbs what
percentage came from Protein that's the
kind of break down I would be interested
in and I strongly suspect there was a
much more uh much larger contribution
from fat and
protein maybe all three were equal but
today it's like 80 90% carbohydrates and
that's why Indians are all skinny fat
and potbellied and all that so yeah that
that's what I think obviously I don't
have sufficient data to conclusively
prove this but I strongly suspect that
Indians ate much more protein back in
the day now what form of protein could
be vegetarian protein could be Dairy
based protein and could be hunting
protein so those
who there were certain classes of
Indians who were the Warriors Etc they
would hunt and they would eat
meat so meat has always been a part of
India's diet at least in some PE for
some people and there have been people
I'm sure whose lineages have been
vegetarian for thousands of years that's
also true
but yeah this is a very interesting
question and I hope and I wish proper
research would be done to answer this
question the answer to this question can
be can be the the Genesis of at least 20
or 30 PhD thesis
actually okay arushi says what are your
opinions on the river saswati is it
still present in any form or completely
dried up is gagra really
Saraswati okay so it's not the gagar
it's a
gagar and most likely the gagar is what
is left of the ancient Saraswati so
every Mount the gagar swells up and she
becomes this gigantic wide river that is
that is just scary to look at and that
is the gagar and and if you read the
Riga the Saraswati is called the mother
of floods and when the gagar swells up
in the monsoon she looks exactly like
the mother of floods
so my opinion of the sarasti is that it
was I think it's conclusively
established now that the sarasti existed
you have papers in in the most
prestigious scientific journal in the
world nature that refer to the sarasti
we know that the great paleo Channel
exists over here you need to know how to
look at it there's this big dried out
River channel that is visible properly
in in scientific uh satellite images it
drained out over here can you see any
River draining out over here in the Run
of cut there's none right so why is this
this why is there this this under C
paleo Channel there is the drainage
channel of a long gone River where's the
river so the river existed no doubt
about it whatsoever and it dried out
because of climate change and what's
left of it in Northern India is this
seasonal intermittent rainfed river
which is today called the gagar
hakra and in the ancient days it
extended all the way to the
sea of sashtra and it was a great
sarasti the mother of floods and the
mother of knowledge and the mother of
Indian
civilization and still woried across the
world even in Japan as
bentin carbs are starvation food and I
hate it
look if you look I'm not saying carbs
are bad okay carbs have a role to play
in in everyone's diet fruits are great
carbs vegetables are great great carbs
even chickpeas and rajma and all that
and and rajma Dal chavel all that stuff
is is carbs I mean everything has its
place in your diet but you your diet
should not be lopsided in One Direction
like 80% 90% you eat carbs then then
imagine how your health will be you need
to have a balance of carbohydrates
proteins and fats so I don't hate carbs
as such I'm nothing I have nothing
against you hating it okay you can feel
free to hate whatever you like it's fine
I don't hate cars I saying that the the
diet that Indians are used to and which
which the diet that they consider to
that consider to be their uh
traditional diet or or or the customary
diet of their ancestors it's not really
so it's the diet that was forced upon
your ancestors due to starvation created
by hundreds of artificial famines
induced by the British and you before
the time of the British Indians most
likely had a very different diet
that's my
point karwat says why are Indians
obsessed with degrees whenever you make
videos on history people are calling you
the fakest I don't have a degree in
history how do I deal with negative
comments will when will this mentality
end I don't care about the negative
comments I it makes absolutely no
difference to me okay it it affects me
not not at all now why are Indians
obsess with decree because of the system
the system the the academic system the
job market Etc it's all based on degrees
the piece of paper you need to have you
may have the best knowledge in the world
you may have the greatest skills in the
world but if you don't have the paper
piece of paper with with a stamp on it
then you will not get a job and the
system has been made such that Indians
that that you can't succeed without
having that that degree in your
hand so that's why Indians are observ
with degrees and today you if you if
you're a business person if you're an
entrepreneur you don't need a degree you
need
skills but still those entrepreneurs
even today their mindset is such that
they will hire when they hire employees
they will look for what's your degree
did you get first class did you get
second class from which institution did
you get your degree all that stuff who
cares but yeah it's going to take time
for this to change if you look at the us
if you look at the the hiring pattern of
of companies like Tesla SpaceX they look
at your skills not your degrees degrees
of course help but skills are more
important eventually it will change it
may take another decade or so perhaps so
yeah I have no degree in history but why
don't you bring me a historian and let's
talk you
know so yeah people say all kinds of
stuff in the comments it makes no
difference what so me what soever to me
I have extremely thick skin people may
not realize that makes no difference I
don't care about anyone's opinions yeah
the only opinion that I care about is a
very few people and my own opinion and
as long as I'm s satisfi that I have
done my job properly I don't care what
people say so I'm good with that it
doesn't affect me all right two hours 10
minutes done I think we should stop over
here we should end over here um thank
you so much for all your questions I
hope I've taken a wide variety of
questions I know there are a thousand
more questions I was not able to take so
all of all those of you whose questions
I could not take I
apologize I will keep doing this every
week as many questions I will take as
possible and I have another live stream
coming up in uh on the 24th I believe
which is uh on the 25th which is going
to be about mainly astrophysics and
Science and the next one about will be
about history and geopolitics so in
those live streams I will take the
questions from the comments not from the
live chat so uh yeah so I will see you
very soon in the next live stream until
then take care thank you so much for
your for your viewership for your
questions I really appreciate it and
I'll see you very soon keep raising your
standards good night good day see you
soon